okay hi everyone we're just about to
好的，大家好，我们即将
start another exciting Tech Talk and
开始另一个激动人心的技术讲座，
carcass is the team of the month for
cas体是本月的团队
sure everyone is buzzing about it and we
确保每个人都在嗡嗡作响，我们
have this great opportunity to have John
有机会拥有约翰
clinger here with us and he will be
克林格在这里和我们在一起，他将
talking about how to build Eclipse micro
谈论如何构建Eclipse micro
profile applications with carcass so
car体的轮廓应用
without really wasting too much time
不会浪费太多时间
I'll just hand it over to John and John
我会交给约翰和约翰
if you want to take it over and go ahead
如果您想接管并继续
sure so I am going to share my screen
可以，所以我要分享我的屏幕
okay everyone see the screen okay I lost
好吧，每个人都看到屏幕好了，我输了
your audio don't know if that's me or
您的音频不知道是我还是
you okay is your screen awesome okay
你好吧，你的屏幕很棒吗
so welcome everyone thanks for taking
所以欢迎大家谢谢
your valuable time out to hear about how
您宝贵的时间来了解如何
to build micro profile apps with Korkis
用Korkis构建微型个人资料应用
and my name is John Klingon I'm a
我叫John Klingon，我是
product manager at Red Hat and also a
Red Hat的产品经理
micro profile committer one of the
微型个人资料提交者之一
co-founders kind of helped start my
联合创始人有点帮助开始我的
profile and my twitter handle is at
个人资料，我的推特手柄位于
Jaclyn so you'll you'll see me chat a
Jaclyn所以你会看到我聊天的
lot about about quark is and it's a
关于夸克的很多东西是
micro profile and stuff like that too so
微观轮廓和类似的东西
I got a few slides and then an awful lot
我有几张幻灯片，然后又很多
of live coding so we'll we'll see how
实时编码，所以我们将看看如何
this goes I'll beg forgiveness now just
这就是我现在要原谅
in case we run into problems okay let me
万一我们遇到问题好吧，让我
see here okay going to talk a little bit
看到这里好了再说一点
about the evolution of the Java stack I
关于Java堆栈的演变
suspect many of you are familiar with
怀疑你们中许多人都熟悉
doing development
做发展
with Java EE right so we've we've got
正确使用Java EE，所以我们已经
this stack this Java stack that's been
这个堆栈这个Java堆栈
optimized for most of the last 20 years
在过去20年的大部分时间里进行了优化
for basically running Java applications
用于基本运行的Java应用程序
and servers right so the expectation is
和服务器正确，所以期望是
that you're running on either directly
您正在直接运行
on hardware or in a virtual machine
在硬件或虚拟机上
you're running a heavy an application
您正在运行大量的应用程序
server running on top of that running on
服务器在服务器上运行
top of the JDK the JDK has been
JDK的顶部
optimized for to a large degree for
在很大程度上进行了优化
running application servers right
正确运行应用程序服务器
running lots of tons of threads a lot of
运行大量的线程
dynamic activity as you deploy none
没有部署时的动态活动
deploy applications and you've got
部署应用程序，您已经
frameworks that have increasingly over
越来越多的框架
time become more and more dynamic and
时间变得越来越充满活力，
that means using a lot of reflection
这意味着要进行大量反思
making a lot of decisions at runtime so
在运行时做出很多决定，所以
we're where we've kind of been moving
我们一直在搬家
over the last three or four years has
在过去的三四年中
been more and more towards micro
越来越倾向于微型
services and as you know Java EE slowed
服务，并且您知道Java EE变慢了
down for a while now it's moving to the
下降了一段时间，现在它正在向
Eclipse Foundation as Jakarta EE but why
Eclipse Foundation命名为Jakarta EE，但是为什么
would it had slowed down for a while
它会放慢一会儿吗
we basically as a community as you know
我们基本上是一个社区，如您所知
whether it's vendors or individuals Java
是供应商还是个人Java
user groups created the Eclipse micro
用户组创建了Eclipse micro
profile right the idea was to continue
正确的想法是继续
the idea of creating specifications that
创建规范的想法
foster you know multiple implementations
培养您知道多种实现
but we do it in a different way than was
但是我们用不同于以往的方式
done with Java EE and even different
使用Java EE完成，甚至有所不同
from I think how Jakarta EE will evolve
我认为Jakarta EE将如何发展
and that basically means we treat micro
这基本上意味着我们对待微
profile a lot like it's an open source
就像它是一个开源一样
community right so it's an open source
社区权利，所以它是一个开源
project I mean so we we have multiple
项目，我的意思是，我们有多个
releases per year we don't necessarily
每年的发行量我们不一定
guarantee backwards compatibility quite
相当保证向后兼容性
like Java EE or even Jakarta EE probably
像Java EE甚至Jakarta EE
plans to write so we consider ourselves
计划写，所以我们考虑自己
a faster-moving community to address the
移动速度更快的社区来解决
needs of
需要
microservices development there's still
微服务开发仍然存在
a lot of movement in this area so if you
这个区域有很多运动，所以如果你
look to the right hand side of this
看看这个的右边
diagram you'll see that there's a
图表中您会看到有一个
healthy set of specifications there's a
健康的规范集有一个
base programming model based on Java EE
Java EE的基础编程模型
with CDI JSON processing and Jason
与CDI JSON处理和Jason
binding and then jax-rs that kind of
绑定，然后用jax-rs
defines the base programming model and
定义基本的编程模型并
on top of that we've got specifications
最重要的是，我们有规格
that define how to utilize
定义如何利用
micro-services patterns with a specific
具有特定功能的微服务模式
set of api's and in the market there's
一套api，在市场上
multiple implementations of these api's
这些api的多种实现
so on the lower left hand side what you
所以在左下角
can see is it's a rather large community
可以看到这是一个相当大的社区
both vendors organizations and
供应商组织和
individuals a very active community
个人是一个非常活跃的社区
micro profile Daioh and in the lower
微型轮廓大王和下
right hand side you see a bunch of
右边你会看到一堆
implementations and Korkis which i'll be
实现和我将成为的Korkis
talking about it is also an
谈论它也是
implementation we just haven't fully run
实施我们还没有完全运行
the micro profile tcks yet but there's
微型配置文件还可以，但是有
also multiple specifications in the
也有多种规格
pipeline meaning in fact one of them is
管道实际上是其中之一
done we have micro profile reactive
完成了我们的微轮廓反应
streams operators and there's a reactive
流运算符，并且有反应
messaging spec context propagation graph
消息传递规范上下文传播图
QL long-running actions so there's lots
QL长期运行的动作，所以有很多
of specifications that are kind of being
规范的存在
baked that should come out probably
可能应该出来的烤
within you know the next six months or
在您知道的未来六个月内，或
so so we continue to evolve pretty
所以我们会继续发展
quickly but again we're evolving in the
很快，但我们又在不断发展
context of micro services development
微服务开发的背景
right now what's interesting is if we
现在有趣的是，如果我们
think about the modern enterprise Java
考虑一下现代企业Java
micro services stack really what we do
微服务真的是我们的工作
is we take the same philosophy that
我们是否遵循相同的哲学
we've had in in many cases the same
在很多情况下，我们都拥有相同的
frameworks that we've had you know over
我们已经让您了解的框架
the last you know 15 years or so and we
您知道的最后15年左右，我们
just applied them towards micro services
刚刚将它们应用于微服务
so instead of deploying multiple apps on
因此，与其在上面部署多个应用
top of a JVM what we what we do is we
JVM的顶部我们要做的是
just deploy single app
只需部署单个应用
averaging again many of the same
再次平均许多相同的
frameworks there are new frameworks
有新的框架
right so Micro profile is a good example
对，因此Micro个人资料就是一个很好的例子
right we've got so far eight or nine
对，我们到目前为止有八九个人
homegrown specs with a bunch more in the
本地规格，还有更多
pipeline like I mentioned so there are
就像我提到的管道，所以有
some new frameworks but the way that
一些新的框架，但是
these frameworks have been evolving is
这些框架一直在发展
if they're still fairly dynamic right
如果他们仍然相当动态吧
they make a lot of runtime decisions and
他们做出很多运行时决策，
even the runtimes underneath like an
甚至是下面的运行时
application server still do a lot of
应用服务器仍然做很多事情
optimizations and decision-making at
的优化和决策
runtime all right so that's what we're
好的运行时，这就是我们要做的
course comes in right quark is basically
当然进来的夸克基本上是
rethinks this and it says well let's
重新考虑这一点，它说的很好，让我们
let's optimize this stack so that we we
让我们优化此堆栈，以便我们
understand that our target environment
了解我们的目标环境
isn't necessarily running multiple
不一定要运行多个
applications on an app server right that
应用服务器上的应用
is by the way monoliths the java ee
顺便说一句Java EE
model that's still available right so um
仍然可用的模型，所以嗯
what we're talking about here is if I'm
我们在这里谈论的是如果我是
specifically targeting micro services
专门针对微服务
and a single app stack that's where
和单个应用堆栈
we're looking at something like like
我们正在寻找类似的东西
Korkis right where I can take these
Korkis对，我可以拿这些
applications and these these frameworks
应用程序以及这些框架
and build them with the understanding
并在理解的基础上建立他们
that it's going to be deployed to a
它将被部署到
kubernetes Linux container based
基于kubernetes Linux容器
environment and that's kind of those two
环境，这两种
icons that you see under the stack all
您在堆栈下看到的所有图标
right
对
that's that's kind of the new target
这就是新的目标
environment that organizations are
组织所处的环境
deploying to and so quark is
部署到夸克是
specifically targets kubernetes and
专门针对kubernetes和
containers so what that means is well in
容器，这意味着在
a kubernetes environment it's it's a
kubernetes环境，这是一个
very it's an immutable environment right
这是一个不变的环境
meaning that when I develop a container
这意味着当我开发一个容器时
I tend not to log into the container and
我倾向于不登录到容器中
make changes right what I do is I make
正确地进行更改我所做的就是
my changes in code and then I run that
我的代码更改，然后运行
code through a pipeline and it redeploys
通过管道进行代码重新部署
a new container right so this is the
一个新的容器，所以这是
idea of a mutable infrastructure so if
可变基础设施的想法，如果
you think about those dynamic frameworks
您考虑那些动态框架
that I've kind of been talking about
我一直在谈论
where we do lots of reflection we're
我们进行了很多反思
making a lot of run
跑很多
decisions in deploying to it what's
部署到它的决定是什么
really an immutable infrastructure so
真正的不变基础架构
Korkis tree thinks that it says well
Korkis树认为它说得很好
let's not target or let's not make a lot
我们不瞄准目标或不赚很多钱
of these decisions at at runtime let's
这些决策在运行时
optimize the frameworks with the
通过优化框架
understanding that I'm targeting
了解我的目标
immutable infrastructure so what we do
不变的基础设施，所以我们要做的
is we do the optimizations things like
是我们做优化之类的事情吗
scanning the classpath or annotations
扫描类路径或注释
pre compiling the results of that into
将结果预先编译成
the the jar file if you're going to run
jar文件（如果要运行）
on top of Java or into the native binary
在Java之上或在本机二进制文件中
if you're going to be running you know
如果您要跑步，您会知道
directly on on the operating system with
直接在操作系统上
it without a JDK so we do a lot of this
它没有JDK，所以我们做了很多
work now at build time with the
现在在构建时使用
understanding that we're going to be
了解我们将成为
deploying two immutable infrastructure
部署两个不变的基础架构
so we're basically optimizing that
所以我们基本上是在优化
entire stack right so you'll see some
整个堆栈正确，所以您会看到一些
examples of this no quark is can run on
这种无夸克的例子可以在
the on the JDK you can put it in
在JDK上，您可以将其放入
production on the JDK if you want to
如果要在JDK上进行生产
alright but you can also compile it down
好吧，但是你也可以把它编译下来
to native binary and in fact in
到本地二进制文件，实际上
development mode we'll run strictly on
开发模式，我们将严格按照
top of the JDK
JDK的顶部
all right I'm gonna do a quick time
好吧，我要快点
check all right now if I do want to
如果我想现在检查所有
compile down to a binary well we utilize
编译为我们利用的二进制井
growl VM to do that growl vm is a pretty
咆哮的虚拟机做到这一点咆哮的虚拟机是一个漂亮的
awesome project for running highly
令人敬畏的项目，可以高度运行
efficient Java code or even dynamic
高效的Java代码甚至是动态的
languages that run on top of the JVM now
现在可以在JVM上运行的语言
Korkis doesn't really focus on that
Korkis并不真正专注于此
aspect of it on the dynamic language
它在动态语言上的方面
aspect as much but it does utilize kind
方面，但它确实利用善良
of those red boxes that you see in this
您在此看到的那些红色方框中
diagram the the growl compiler or to
图咆哮编译器或
compile it down to a native code and we
编译成本地代码，我们
really focus mostly on the Java language
真正专注于Java语言
although we do support Kotlin running on
尽管我们确实支持Kotlin在
top of Korkis as well all right and
Korkis的顶部以及所有
underlying even inside of your binary
甚至在您的二进制文件内部
there's still a virtual machine running
仍然有一个虚拟机在运行
but its role is is greatly reduced
但是它的作用大大降低了
compared to just running
与刚跑步相比
OpenJDK with with a hotspot vm so what
具有热点vm的OpenJDK怎么办
Korkis utilizes grow vm for is both
Korkis利用生长vm既是
native compilation and dead code
本机编译和无效代码
elimination so one of the things that
消除，所以其中之一是
we've done with Korkis is we've
我们对Korkis所做的就是
optimized a lot of the libraries so that
优化了很多库，以便
we reduce dependencies both within the
我们减少了
library and even across libraries and
图书馆，甚至跨图书馆
what this means that if your application
这意味着如果您的应用程序
doesn't use some of the code it'll be
不使用某些代码
eliminated during the compilation phase
在编译阶段消除
and that means you get a relatively
那意味着你得到一个相对
small executable binary ok ok so let's
小可执行二进制文件，好吧，让我们
do a little bit of live coding ok so um
做一些现场编码好吧
can everyone see let's see here I'm
大家可以看看我们在这里吗
gonna make this bigger I do have the
会变得更大，我确实有
chat open in another monitor so if folks
聊天在另一台显示器上打开，所以如果人们
want to ask questions or make comments
想问问题或发表评论
about bit you know being able to see the
关于你知道能够看到
code I write and stuff just just let me
我写的代码和东西只是让我
know
知道
alright so to create a project with
好吧，所以创建一个项目
Korkis what we're going to do is we're
Korkis我们要做的是
going to use the Quercus maven plugin so
要使用Quercus maven插件，所以
this will actually generate the outline
这实际上会产生轮廓
of us a very simple restful endpoint we
我们一个非常简单的宁静终点
are working on kind of a web-based
正在基于网络
starter as well but for now what we're
也是首发，但现在我们是
going to be using is the maven plug-in
将要使用的是Maven插件
to generate the source code so what you
生成源代码，所以你
can see here is I'm just pre providing
可以看到这里是我刚刚提供的
the maven artifact information that I
我的Maven工件信息
want to be generated for this right well
希望为此而产生
for this project right what the group
对于这个项目，什么小组
idea is the artifact idea here we're
想法是工件的想法，我们在这里
going to call it person we're gonna
我们要称呼它
create a restful resource called person
创建一个称为人员的宁静资源
resource and it'll be listening at the
资源，它将在
person endpoint hey I'm gonna go ahead
人端点，嘿，我要继续
and create this alright so if I want to
并创建这个好吧，所以如果我想
take a look at the source code real
看一下真实的源代码
quickly what you see is it is you know
很快你看到的是你知道
kind of like what I said it's a very
就像我说的那样
simple restful endpoint now
现在简单的宁静端点
let's add some additional maven
让我们添加一些其他的专家
dependencies so that we can build out an
依赖关系，以便我们可以建立一个
actual micro profile application so
实际的微轮廓应用程序
Korkis again with the maven plug-in has
Korkis再次使用了Maven插件
something has a goal called list
有一个目标叫清单
extensions an extension in Quercus is
扩展Quercus中的扩展是
basically what i mentioned it's a pretty
基本上我提到的是一个漂亮的
optimized framework that well it's
优化的框架
optimized for efficiency like I
像我一样优化效率
mentioned before but it's also you can
之前提到过，但是你也可以
assume that if it's in a chorus
假设它在合唱中
extension it could also be compiled down
扩展它也可以被编译下来
to a native binary not all the
到本地二进制文件
frameworks out in the Java ecosystem can
Java生态系统中的框架可以
be compiled down to a native binary
编译成本地二进制文件
without some extra work and we've kind
没有一些额外的工作，我们很友善
of done that extra work on behalf of the
代表做了额外的工作
developer for these frameworks so if we
这些框架的开发者，所以如果我们
take a look at the extensions we've got
看看我们拥有的扩展
our keys our CDI implementation for
我们的关键是我们的CDI实现
Korkis you see we got some camel
Korkis，你看到我们有一些骆驼
extensions flyweight and other database
扩展flyweight和其他数据库
related extensions hibernate some JDBC
相关扩展休眠了一些JDBC
drivers let's see what else we have in
司机让我们看看我们还有什么
Finnish band supports as a client Jason
芬兰乐队支持杰森
consuming and producing Jason via Jason
通过Jason消费和生产Jason
binding and processing key cloak for
绑定和处理密钥斗篷
security kubernetes I hope to have time
我希望有时间安全kubernetes
to show that one it generates the amyl
证明它能产生戊基
that enables you to take your
使您能够
application and deploy it into a
应用程序并将其部署到
kubernetes environment Catelyn I
kubernetes环境Catelyn I
mentioned see you got transactions all
提到看到所有交易
these small right ones are basically
这些小的正确的基本上
micro profile spec implementations right
微型配置文件规范的实现正确
so you can see context propagation fault
这样就可以看到上下文传播错误
tolerance Health metrics a lot of those
耐受性健康指标很多
are implemented in the small right
在小权利中实施
project and kafka support and all that
项目和kafka支持以及所有这些
all right so that's quite a big list so
好吧，那是一个很大的清单，所以
what I'm going to do now is and here is
我现在要做的就是
show you a how to add some extensions to
向您展示如何向其中添加一些扩展
our project so what we're going to do is
我们的项目，所以我们要做的是
use the add extension
使用添加扩展名
goal and we're gonna specify the
目标，我们将指定
extensions oops if I could spell
如果我能拼写，扩展哎呀
properly alright so one of the nice
很好，所以很好的之一
things about this extension is you don't
关于这个扩展的事情是你不
have to necessarily type in the entire
必须输入整个
strings that you see here you can just
您在这里看到的字符串
type in a subset and if it can find
输入子集，如果可以找到
without any kind of name it without any
没有任何名字
kind of name collision it'll add it
一种名称冲突，它将添加它
alright so let's do a Kubb I mentioned
好吧，让我们做一个我提到的Kubb
that for doing kubernetes ya mole
为了做kubernetes ya mole
generation fault tolerance let's use the
代容错性让我们使用
micro profile restclient I'm going to
我要去的微型个人资料restclient
show that I'm gonna show some metrics
表明我要显示一些指标
I'm gonna show open API and swagger this
我将展示开放的API并夸大其词
one I'm not about because we will hit a
我不想要的，因为我们将击中
namespace collision Korkis rest easy
命名空间冲突Korkis轻松自在
Jason binding let's see I'm gonna do
Jason binding让我们看看我要去做
panache panache is a layer and ease of
panache panache是​​一层又容易
use layer on top of GPA and hibernate so
在GPA之上使用层并休眠
that'll be interesting show I'm gonna
那将是一个有趣的节目，我要
show we're going to use the h2 database
展示我们将使用h2数据库
while we're developing locally so that
当我们在本地发展时
we use in memory database but when we go
我们在内存数据库中使用，但是当我们去时
into production on our kubernetes
在我们的kubernetes上投入生产
cluster which I have running on my
我在我的集​​群上运行的集群
laptop please post Chris and we'll use
笔记本电脑，请张贴克里斯，我们将使用
micro profile health check we'll see how
微型个人资料运行状况检查，我们将看看
much of this we can actually get to
我们实际上可以得到的很多
during this hour so now this is going to
在这个小时里，所以现在
fail because we actually ran into a
失败，因为我们实际上遇到了
namespace collision I mentioned post
我提到过的命名空间冲突
Chris but there's actually two different
克里斯，但实际上有两个不同
post CRA's database drivers one for you
为您发布CRA的数据库驱动程序
for using the async reactive driver the
用于使用异步反应驱动程序
other one for using a standard JDBC
另一个用于使用标准JDBC
driver so what I'm going to do is choose
司机，所以我要做的就是选择
the standard JDBC one and we'll fix that
标准的JDBC，我们将对其进行修复
okay so that was added now I'm gonna do
好的，现在添加了，我要去做
one other kind of a little bit of pre
另一种预
optimization here in this for this
为此在此进行优化
project and I'm gonna set an
项目，我要设置一个
environmental variable so I'm gonna set
环境变量，所以我要设置
Quercus on task or profile equals dev so
任务或配置文件上的Quercus等于dev这样
this is going to come in handy when we
这将在我们使用时派上用场
using micro profile config where we can
使用微配置文件配置，我们可以
have different configuration profiles
具有不同的配置文件
one for development and one for
一个用于发展，另一个用于
production all right now I'm going to
生产现在我要去
open this all up into Visual Studio code
将这些全部打开到Visual Studio代码中
of course you can use your favorite IDE
当然，您可以使用自己喜欢的IDE
again well let's take a look at the palm
好吧，让我们来看看手掌
file and you'll see we're using version
文件，您会看到我们正在使用版本
17 of quark is this is the most recent
夸克17是最新的
version and you could see all these
版本，您可以看到所有这些
maven dependencies that we just added
我们刚刚添加的Maven依赖项
with an extension okay and there's also
扩展好了，还有
if we want to compile down to native
如果我们想编译成本地的
code one of the things you'll see is a
编码，您将看到的一件事是
pro maven profile called native and
pro maven配置文件称为native和
that'll let us generate a native binary
让我们生成一个本地二进制文件
I'm gonna try to minimize that because
我要尽量减少这种情况，因为
it takes a while and we don't have a lot
需要一段时间，我们没有很多
of time to show an awful lot of
有时间展示很多
functionality so I'm going to create a
功能，所以我要创建一个
terminal now what I'm going to do is put
终端现在我要做的就是放
Quercus in development mode actually I
我在开发模式中的Quercus
should have set the profile here so in
应该在这里设置配置文件
fact when we do that in this terminal
事实上，当我们在此终端中执行此操作时
window now we're gonna run Quercus in
窗口，现在我们要运行Quercus
developer mode so I can develop this
开发人员模式，以便我可以开发
project
项目
maven quark is : dev so what this is
夸克夸克是：开发人员，这是什么
gonna do it's it's going to open up a
要去做，这将打开一个
debugging endpoint if I want to do the
如果我想调试端点
bugging I don't think I'm gonna show
我不觉得我会表现出来
that here again because of time and then
一次又一次因为时间
it actually runs the app now let's see
它实际上正在运行该应用程序，现在让我们看看
here I am going to pull over
在这里我要把车停下来
a another window and we're gonna go to
另一个窗口，我们要去
localhost colon 8080 /ui
localhost 冒号8080 / ui
so micro profile has open API support
因此，微型配置文件具有开放的API支持
and that's what's kind of underlying
这就是潜在的一种
this endpoint Korkis supports the an
该端点Korkis支持
embedded swagger user interface so you
嵌入式swagger用户界面，使您
can try out the restful endpoints that
可以尝试宁静的端点
you create in this case it's a simple
您在这种情况下创建的方法很简单
hello world so oops actually want to
你好，世界，所以哎呀实际上要
extend that so let's actually try out
扩展一下，让我们实际尝试一下
the the restful endpoint I may have to
我可能要面对的宁静的终点
make this bigger okay
让这个更大吧
and we're going to execute the endpoint
我们将执行端点
and you'll see that responds with hello
您会看到它以“你好”回应
now I'm not going to be using the
现在我将不会使用
browser to interact with the application
浏览器与应用程序进行交互
because that I want to have to
因为我想要
constantly switch back and forth between
不断地在之间来回切换
the browser and and the application so
浏览器和应用程序
I'm going to do most of the work
我将做大部分工作
directly in in the IDE and a terminal
直接在IDE和终端中
okay so so you can kind of check check
好吧，所以你可以检查一下
box off the fact that micah profile
取消micah个人资料这一事实
supports open api out of the box so i'm
支持开箱即用的开放式api，所以我
gonna go back to actually the
要回到实际上
presentation here go fullscreen and talk
演示文稿在这里全屏讨论
a little bit about micro profile config
关于微型配置文件的一些信息
good micro profile
良好的微轮廓
sorry good micro services development
对不起，良好的微服务开发
style you know kind of a twelve factor
你知道的十二种风格
app is you want to externalize your
应用是您要外部化您的
application configuration and you could
应用程序配置，您可以
do that with micro profile config where
使用微配置文件配置来做到这一点
you can inject the value of a property
您可以注入属性的值
into your application and behind the
进入您的应用程序并在
scenes there's multiple property sources
场景中有多个属性来源
config sources right so you can specify
配置资源正确，因此您可以指定
a property using a java property on the
使用java属性的属性
command line or you could set an
命令行，也可以设置一个
environmental variable that's the middle
中间的环境变量
box on the bottom or you can define it
底部的方框，也可以定义它
in a micro profile - config dot
在微型配置文件中-配置点
properties file now our Quercus does it
属性文件，现在我们的Quercus做到了
does support that micro profile config
确实支持该微型配置文件配置
properties file but it also supports an
属性文件，但它也支持
application type properties file and
应用程序类型属性文件和
that's the one I'll be using during this
那是我在此期间要使用的那个
presentation and you could also create
演示文稿，您也可以创建
custom config sources so you could
自定义配置源，因此您可以
create a config source for vault for
为Vault创建配置源
eureka whatever right there's other
尤里卡无论有什么权利
event config sources out there in fact
实际上，事件配置源
there's a micro profile extensions
有一个微型个人资料扩展名
project that actually extends a lot of
实际上扩展了很多项目
these capabilities of micro profile so
这些微轮廓的功能
micro github I think it's a github comm
微型github我认为这是一个github通讯
slash micro profile - extensions project
slash micro profile-扩展项目
alright so let's go back and do a little
好吧，让我们回去做一点
bit of
一点
coding so I am going to bring up oops
编码，所以我要提起糟糕
not test mein Java person resource here
在这里不测试我的Java人员资源
we go
我们去
so this is this is the code that was
所以这是原来的代码
generated now what we're going to do is
现在生成的我们要做的是
add in the ability to inject resources
增加注入资源的能力
from an external location all right so
从外部位置可以
let's do at inject config property this
让我们在注入配置属性
is a micro profile API let's make sure
是一个微型配置文件API，请确保
we choose the right one let's see what
我们选择合适的，让我们看看
is it here we want to do name is going
我们要在这里做名字吗
to be greeting and we're also going to
问候，我们也将
give it a default value just so we can
给它一个默认值，以便我们可以
test it out right now and the default
现在进行测试并使用默认设置
value is going to be hello okay and
价值将是你好，而且
we're going to inject this into a string
我们将其注入字符串中
variable reading down here we're just
在这里阅读变量，我们只是
going to return greeting all right so
要回去问候好吧
let's go back to I think create a new
让我们回到我认为创建一个新的
terminal window
终端窗口
and I'm just going to use the HTTP ie
而我只是要使用HTTP即
kind of command line tool so you just
一种命令行工具，所以您只是
type HTTP and then the URL that you want
键入HTTP，然后输入所需的URL
to access so we're going to do an HTTP
访问，所以我们要做一个HTTP
localhost colon 8080 slash / sincere got
localhost 冒号8080斜杠/真诚得到
hello now what you may not have noticed
你好现在你可能没有注意到
is that I didn't have to compile
是我不必编译
anything I didn't have to hit control-c
我不需要按Control-C的任何内容
recompile and then restart the app right
重新编译然后重新启动应用程序吧
so Korkis is actually live loading all
所以Korkis实际上是实时加载所有
the changes that i'm making as they make
我所做的改变
them right and it doesn't not just for
他们是对的，这不仅是为了
code but also for properties in the
代码，也可以用于
property file so let's go ahead and do
属性文件，让我们继续进行
that
那
oops here we go application DEP
糟糕，我们去应用DEP
properties so we're gonna do here is
属性，所以我们要在这里做的是
we're gonna add a greeting and here
我们要在这里添加问候
let's see we want to call it oh okay
让我们看看我们想称它为好吧
okay yeah I'll do hola there we go and
好吧，我会去呼啦，我们去
it's at the endpoint again and what
又在终点了
we'll see is that
我们会看到的是
get up out of the property file so
起床离开属性文件，以便
there's an order of precedence with
有一个优先顺序
micah profile right where the look at
micah配置文件在哪里看
the config file first and pull it out of
首先配置文件并将其拉出
there you can override that by using an
在那里您可以使用
environmental variable and you can eat
环境变量，你可以吃
override both of those if you use a Java
如果您使用Java，请同时覆盖两者
system property right bye - dee greeting
系统财产权再见-迪问候语
okay so that's pretty cool now let's
好吧，那很酷，现在让我们
take a look at another API the micro
看一下另一个API
profile rest client
个人资料其余客户
so with jax-rs the red building out a a
因此，与jax-rs一起，红色建筑就成了
REST API takes a little bit of work it
REST API需要一些工作
uses a builder pattern to interact with
使用构建器模式与之交互
a restful service with a micro profile
微观特征的宁静服务
rest client what it does is it takes a
休息客户要做的是
very type safe approach to doing
非常安全的做法
development of a restful client so for
开发一个宁静的客户，以便
interacting with a restful service
与宁静的服务互动
really you're just manipulating a Java
真的，您只是在操纵Java
object alright so let's go ahead and
好的，让我们继续吧，
build out a restful client so um go back
建立一个宁静的客户，所以回去
to our code and what's also nice about
到我们的代码，还有什么好处
the restful client is there's gifts rid
宁静的客户有没有礼物
of some of the boilerplate so I'm gonna
一些样板，所以我要
go find our project here oh I moved to
去这里找到我们的项目哦，我搬到了
file
文件
on accident I'm gonna just delete that
偶然地我要删除那个
earlier when I was scrolling up I
早些时候我向上滚动时
accidentally copied a file all right
意外复制了文件
here we go let's go back here and now
这里我们走，让我们回到这里，现在
we're gonna create a new file we're
我们要创建一个新文件
gonna call this the hello rest client
要称呼它为您好休息的客户
dot Java all right
点Java可以了
and we
和我们
a package and what we're to do is create
一个包，我们要做的就是创建
a an interface interface hello rest
一个接口接口你好休息
client now we have to annotate this
客户现在我们必须对此进行注释
interface with a couple of things the
与几件事接口
first is register rest client okay and
首先是注册其余客户，然后
we that's going to register this this
我们将要注册这个
restful client so that we can actually
宁静的客户，以便我们实际上可以
inject it in our actual application code
将其注入我们的实际应用程序代码中
so next I'm going to do is at path so
所以接下来我要走的路是
which end point is this going to access
这将访问哪个端点
slash and what is the the remote service
斜杠和远程服务是什么
what is the remote services method
什么是远程服务方法
signature look like from an you know
签名看起来像从你知道
method and if the HTT and for HTTP
方法以及HTT和HTTP
endpoint look like so we're going to use
端点看起来像这样，我们将使用
a get and we're going to produce juices
得到，我们将生产果汁
a media type no that's not what I wanted
媒体类型不，那不是我想要的
that was bad auto completion there the
那是不好的自动完成
type dot text plane okay and the mess
键入点文字平面好，乱七八糟
it is just going to be public string
这只是公开字符串
hello so basically in my we gotta fix
你好，所以基本上我要解决
our imports and what the jax-rs produces
我们的进口以及jax-rs生产的产品
there we go
我们去
so what this is whenever I invoke this
所以什么时候我调用这个
this end point or sorry invoke this
这个终点还是抱歉
method it's going to call the restful
方法，它将称为宁静
endpoint but one of the things we need
端点，但我们需要做的事情之一
to do is point to the URL where the
要做的就是指向URL
actual end point is so I can either
实际的终点是，我可以
specify that I think here or I can
指定我认为在这里或我可以
specify it in the property file and so
在属性文件中指定它，如此
what I'm going to do is specify this in
我要做的是在
the property file all right so I'm gonna
财产文件还可以，所以我要
go back to actually I have to show
回到实际上我必须证明
something slightly different first I was
首先我有点不同
gonna go back to the command line but
要回到命令行，但是
instead I'm gonna show you the fact that
相反，我要告诉你的事实是
I've already got a hello service running
我已经在运行hello服务
so basically I have to start it the
所以基本上我必须开始
hello service is the code that was
你好服务是以前的代码
basically generated when I generated
当我生成时基本上生成
this project at first right it's just a
首先这个项目只是一个
response hello or was some other message
回复你好或是其他消息
so what I did is I took that and I
所以我所做的就是我接受了
actually compiled it down to a native
实际上将其编译为本地
binary and deployed it to kubernetes and
二进制并将其部署到kubernetes和
if you take a look here real quick what
如果你看看这里真的很快
you'll see if I look at the actual log
您会看到我是否查看实际的日志
you'll see that this actually started in
您会看到这实际上是从
39 milliseconds right which is actually
正确的是39毫秒
kind of slow normally this starts in
通常是从慢开始
like 10 milliseconds but I have lots of
大概10毫秒，但是我有很多
things going on right now on a machine
机器上正在发生的事情
so that's pretty impressive for a java
因此对于Java来说，这是非常令人印象深刻的
application right alright so what I need
申请权还不错，所以我需要
is the endpoint it's a number
是端点，是数字
back to my source code I'm going to open
回到我的源代码，我要打开
up the property file and I'm going to
上属性文件，我要
paste this in what I can now what I have
将此粘贴到我现在可以拥有的内容中
to do is provide the property that the
要做的就是提供
micro profile rest client will read and
微型个人资料其余客户将阅读并
there's a specific pattern for that the
有一个特定的模式
pattern basically starts with the name
模式基本上以名称开头
of the package so I'm going to copy that
的包装，所以我要复制
because it's convenient dot the name of
因为方便点了
the the class lo restclient
该类lo restclient
followed by MP rest followed by the URL
然后是MP休息，然后是URL
okay so this is going to be the endpoint
好吧，这将是终点
and I think I need also have to add
而且我认为我还必须添加
hello
你好
so micro profile rest client will read
因此，微型个人资料其余客户将阅读
this property and figure out this is the
这个属性，找出这是
endpoint I need to access and into the
我需要访问并进入
Java binding Java object binding if I
Java绑定Java对象绑定（如果我
need to okay so see that let's go back
需要好的，所以让我们回去
to our client now here we have to inject
现在在这里给我们的客户
the restful client right so at inject
宁静的客户权利，所以在注入
now we're going to do at rest client
现在我们要去休息的客户
okay and we are going to then have our
好吧，我们将要拥有我们的
hello rest client I'll call it a hello
你好，休息客户，我会打个招呼
client alright
好的客户
so sorry I'm to do that a few different
很抱歉，我要这样做一些不同
things going on in the background I'm
我在后台发生的事情
trying to stop okay
试图停止好
now this should actually inject our
现在这实际上应该注入我们的
hello client proxy directly into the
你好客户端代理直接进入
hello client variable and then invoke
你好客户端变量，然后调用
what when I actually invoked the hello
当我实际调用你好
method it'll actually make the remote
方法实际上将使遥控器
call so what I'm going to do here is do
打电话，所以我在这里要做的是
hello client dot hello right so let's
你好客户点你好吧，让我们
cross our fingers and make sure this
交叉我们的手指，并确保这
actually works and it did so it's it's
实际有效，确实做到了
calling howdy which is the message
叫你好，这是消息
that's actually predefined in the hello
实际上是在hello中预定义的
service running in the CUDA at ease
轻松在CUDA中运行的服务
runtime right which is OpenShift
运行时权限是OpenShift
okay so let's head over back to our
好吧，让我们回到我们的
slides if we can now what's nice is
如果我们现在可以幻灯片的话，很好的是
again you didn't see me recompile you
再次，你没有看到我重新编译你
know all I had to do is say didn't have
知道我要做的就是说没有
to rebuild recompile restart a very nice
重建重建重新启动非常好
natural flow towards doing development
自然流向发展
now since we're making a remote call
现在，因为我们正在拨打远程电话
we're gonna add some fault tolerance
我们将增加一些容错能力
support into our application so how do
支持我们的应用程序，怎么办
we deal with failure if the low service
如果服务水平低，我们会处理失败
happens to be down so in fact let's even
碰巧掉下来，所以实际上我们甚至
let's even do that let's actually no
让我们这样做，实际上不
I'll do that in a second so what
我待会再做
strategies do we have to deal with fault
我们必须处理错误的策略
tolerance well I can use the
宽容我可以用
asynchronous annotation and run a method
异步注释并运行方法
call in in a different thread I can use
在我可以使用的其他线程中调用
a bulkhead that basically limits the
基本上限制了
number of concurrent accesses to a
并发访问次数
resource so that you're not going to
资源，这样您就不会
overload it circuit breaking a lot of
电路过载使很多
you probably understand what that is but
你可能知道那是什么，但是
basically let you fail fast and it will
基本上让您快速失败，它会
occasionally check the remote service to
偶尔检查远程服务以
see if it's up and if it's up then it
看看是否上升，然后上升
will call it and if it's not it'll
将调用它，如果不是，它将
potentially do a fallback and that's the
可能会进行回退，这就是
next annotation so if you're making a
下一个注释，所以如果您要
method call and that method happens to
方法调用，而该方法恰好
fail
失败
you can provide alternative logic with
您可以提供替代逻辑
the fallback annotation I'll be showing
我将显示的后备注释
that one if you happen to have a failure
如果您碰巧失败了
you can also use retry logic with the
您还可以将重试逻辑与
retry annotation some might think that's
重试注释，有些人可能认为是
an anti-pattern but
反模式，但
if you have an unstable network it could
如果您的网络不稳定，则可能
actually come in kind of handy and then
其实有点方便，然后
the last one is a timeout if you want to
最后一个是超时，如果你想
make sure that you provide a responsive
确保您提供响应
well response back to your to your
很好地回应您对您的
client you can limit the amount of time
客户您可以限制时间
your remote call might make so you can
您的远程呼叫可能会拨打，因此您可以
set it though it'll throw a timeout
设置它虽然会抛出超时
exception if it exceeds some threshold
如果超过某个阈值，则为异常
so what I'm going to do here is we're
所以我要在这里做的是
going to take this call in fact I think
我想接这个电话
at this point I can just get rid of the
在这一点上，我可以摆脱
the endpoint that you with that big
那个大你的终点
jax-rs endpoint and just simply making a
jax-rs端点，只是简单地
method call and what we're going to do
方法调用以及我们要做的事情
is we're going to basically make this a
是我们将基本上使它成为
timeout and after a certain period of
超时和一定时间后
time if we don't get a response then
时间，如果我们没有回应，那么
it's going to return with a timeout
它会超时返回
exception okay and let's see here I
好的，让我们在这里看看
think I need to import that and now
想我现在需要导入
there's two parameters I can provide one
我可以提供两个参数
is the unit so unit of time I'll just
是单位，所以我只是时间单位
leave it at the default which is
将其保留为默认值
milliseconds and it's also going to by
毫秒，也要等到
default take one second 2,000
默认需要一秒钟2,000
milliseconds but we'll just make this
毫秒，但我们只做这个
shorter we'll say what was it value
简短一点，我们会说它有什么价值
equals a half a millisecond right so
等于半毫秒，所以
it's going to timeout after a half a
半分钟后将要超时
millisecond we're also going to provide
毫秒，我们还将提供
a fallback method so if this method
后备方法，所以如果此方法
fails through because of some exception
由于某些异常而失败
then what we're gonna do is provide some
那我们要做的就是提供一些
fallback logic so what we're going to do
后备逻辑，所以我们要做的是
is specify a fallback method we're gonna
指定要使用的备用方法
call it hello
打个招呼吧
fall back okay now what
现在回去好吗
to do is provide the fallback method
要做的是提供后备方法
oops sorry about that go down here and
哎呀，对不起，去这里，
say public and the fallback method just
说公开和后备方法只是
has to have the same method signature as
必须具有与以下方法相同的方法签名
the method that the fallback annotation
后备注释的方法
is on so public stringing we're gonna
是在公开穿线，我们要
call it hello fallback and it has to
叫你好后备，它必须
return a string all right so I'm gonna
返回一个字符串好吧，我要
return and this is Doubtfire there we go
返回，这是“怀疑之火”，我们去了
so I am now going to rerun this
所以我现在要重新运行
application and hold on a second here ah
申请并在这里等一下啊
I forgot to do something let me switch
我忘了做些让我切换的事情
gears here real quick I'm gonna add a
齿轮这里真的很快，我要添加一个
little bit of JPA logic first like
一点点的JPA逻辑首先像
actually should I do I want to do it
实际上我应该做吗
that way this the problem with live
这样生活的问题
coding there's so many different paths
编码有很多不同的路径
you can take um actually no we'll just
你可以拿嗯，实际上不，我们只是
do it this way I guess so
我猜是这样的
oh I took the endpoint off so let's just
哦，我摘掉了终点，让我们
do it this way here real quick we'll add
用这种方式做到这一点，我们将很快添加
it back in it gets and a path there we
它回到它里面，那里有一条路
go oh no just acted as only thing I
走吧，哦，不，我只是作为唯一的角色
think we need okay so now it's calling
认为我们需要没事，所以现在
okay uh I went out of order here a
好吧，我在这里出故障了
little bit of what I was intending to do
我打算做的一点
so I'm gonna go back and go back in
所以我要回去再回去
order so first we're gonna do a JP
点餐，所以我们先来做一个JP
entity using panache and then we're
实体使用panache，然后我们
actually gonna rely on the fallback
实际上要依靠后备
method so let's actually go ahead and
方法，所以让我们实际去吧
create a new file we're gonna call this
创建一个新文件，我们将其称为
person dot Java alright so with with
人点Java还可以
person
人
we may get a GPA entity I am with a GP
我们可能会得到一个GPA实体，我在一个GP中
entity
实体
it's basically an annotated Java Bean
它基本上是一个带注释的Java Bean
right in a lot of ways but what we're
在很多方面都正确，但是我们
going to do is we're going to use
我们要做的就是使用
something called panache and to use
一种叫做panache的东西
panache we're going to extend panache
Panache我们将扩展Panache
entity and for some reason I am NOT
实体，由于某种原因我不是
getting auto completion on that so let
得到自动完成，所以让
me go back to my palm
我回到我的手掌
do I have panache in here yes I do hold
我在这里有松饼吗？
on
上
entity let me try that there we go oh
实体让我尝试去那里哦
did it do that would be nice that was
这样做会很好吗
the problem and we are going to import
问题，我们将要导入
the JPA entity all right now I get some
JPA实体现在可以得到一些
really nice things with panache
真的很棒
typically you would have to create
通常，您必须创建
private fields with getters and setters
带有getter和setter的私有字段
but with panache you can just make them
但是用煎饼你可以把它们做成
public fields so we're gonna miss a
公共领域，所以我们会想念一个
public string name and public int age
公共字符串名称和公共整数年龄
right and I could annotate these with JP
对的，我可以用JP注释这些
annotations like you know at column I
像您在第一列中知道的注释
can put in hibernate validator
可以放入休眠验证器
constraints and so on in the interest of
约束等
time I'm not going to do that but at
时间我不会那样做，但是
this point this is basically a JPA
这一点基本上是一个JPA
entity now what we're going to do is go
现在我们要做的就是去
back to our code and let's provide a new
回到我们的代码，让我们提供一个新的
method get and at path we'll say list
方法get和at path我们会说list
all going to list all the entities in
全部列出所有实体
the database and we are going to produce
数据库，我们将产生
I think it imported the wrong one
我认为这是输入错误的
no I produces produces produces that's
不，我生产的产品是
the wrong one all right sir
错误的一位好先生
that produces where we adhere jax-rs
产生我们坚持jax-rs的地方
version of that okay media type dots
可以的媒体类型点的版本
we're going to return a Jason
我们要归还杰森
application Jason and why am I getting
应用程序杰森，为什么我得到
application do I have the right media
应用程序我有正确的媒体吗
type no I don't for some reason I'm
键入否，我出于某种原因不参加
having a hard time today importing the
今天很难导入
right packages okay it's dark over here
合适的包裹好吧，这里很黑
come on media type and we want the
来媒体类型，我们希望
jax-rs version of that Jason okay
Jason的jax-rs版本好了
finally turn that now we're going to
终于把它变成现在，我们要
return the list of all the persons in
返回所有人员列表
the database so we're going to return
数据库，所以我们要返回
let's see public list of person list all
让我们看看所有人的公开名单
and now because we don't have a name
现在因为我们没有名字
query we're going to use a nice
查询我们将使用一个不错的
convenience method in the panache base
在panache基地的便利方法
class called
类称为
person dot find all right is that find
人点找到好吧就是找到
all there we go
我们走了
and return that as a list of entities
并将其作为实体列表返回
now we got to fix our imports a public
现在我们要公开修复进口
list must return oh I haven't returned
清单必须返回哦，我还没有回来
it that would be nice now
现在那会很好
try and actually hit the end point list
尝试并实际到达终点列表
all and it's gonna fail because we
全部都会失败，因为我们
haven't defined our application
尚未定义我们的应用程序
properties for the JPA datasource so
JPA数据源的属性，因此
what I'm going to do this is where I'm
我要做的就是在这里
going to do a little bit of cheating I'm
我要作弊一点
gonna copy and paste alright so what
要复制并粘贴好了吗
I've got now is a development in
我现在有一个发展
development mode I'm going to talk to
我要谈的开发模式
the h2 in memory database and in
H2在内存数据库和
production we're going to talk to
我们要谈的生产
Postgres now this is where that profile
Postgres现在这是该配置文件所在的位置
comes in
进来
so with Korkis if you have an
所以如果您有Korkis
environmental variable or property set
环境变量或属性集
called Korkis and the square profile
叫做Korkis和方形的轮廓
it'll actually then utilize that profile
然后实际上将利用该配置文件
name here and select the properties with
在这里命名并选择属性
that profile name right so i specified
该配置文件名称正确，所以我指定了
dev as the profile right so i prefix
开发人员作为配置文件的权利，所以我前缀
this these with the dev profile now
这些现在与开发人员简介
let's go ahead and try this and I'm
让我们继续尝试这个，我
still running into errors let's see here
仍然遇到错误，让我们在这里看到
no database driver is specified
未指定数据库驱动程序
did I not hold on dev make sure I set my
我没有坚持开发，确保我设置了我的
might my profile correctly okay and
我的个人资料可能还可以，并且
still having problems because I wonder
仍然有问题，因为我想知道
if I have the h2 database driver in my
如果我有h2数据库驱动程序
palm this is the live coding the problem
手掌这是现场编码的问题
with live coding no h2 is there right
使用实时编码没有h2是正确的
here now you're all probably screaming
现在你可能都在尖叫
at me right now saying you forgot
现在对我说你忘了
something no dialogue driver specified
没有指定对话驱动程序的内容
by Quercus database that data source not
通过Quercus数据库得知数据源不
driver okay
司机还好
go back oh I didn't save the file I
回去哦，我没有保存文件
think that was it actually okay
认为实际上还可以
that didn't work either this is actually
那没有用或者这实际上是
quite embarrassing
很尴尬
okay I have I saved the property file go
好，我已经保存了属性文件
back to person list that should work why
返回应该起作用的人列表为什么
is that not working well person table
是不是工作得很好的人表
the table person is not found so that
找不到表人，因此
means I forgot to do something here I
表示我忘了在这里做些事
forgot to basically set drop and create
忘了基本设置放置和创建
so there was no database table so we
所以没有数据库表，所以我们
have to drop and create the database
必须删除并创建数据库
table that's what the problem is all
这就是问题所在
right so there we go now it worked
对，所以我们现在就去工作了
sorry about that but the nice thing is
对此感到抱歉，但好事是
I'm running into all these problems
我遇到了所有这些问题
because of my poor coding style but I'm
因为我的编码风格很差，但是我
never having to restart right so I guess
永远不需要重新启动，所以我猜
you might say that I'm actually failing
你可能会说我实际上在失败
fast so so now we're talking to a
快速，所以现在我们正在与
database let's do one other thing with
数据库让我们做另一件事
the database let's make sure that we can
数据库，请确保我们可以
add a person right so now we're going to
添加一个人，所以现在我们要
use at post we're going to do a produces
在后期使用，我们将要进行生产
and consumes of adjacent data type and
并消耗相邻数据类型和
we're going to public persons so we're
我们要去找公众人士
gonna return the person that we're
要回报我们的人
adding edie person we're going to be
添加edie人，我们将成为
adding a person person now the way that
现在添加一个人的方式
you add with panache
你加上煎饼
again there's no named query there's no
再次没有命名查询，也没有
entity manager involved directly in the
实体经理直接参与
code that you write what we're just
您编写的代码仅仅是我们的代码
going to do is we're just going to call
我们要做的就是打电话
a person dot persist method we're
一个人点坚持方法
inheriting that from the parent class
从父类继承
right and then we're going to return
对，然后我们要返回
that same person so that's pretty cool
那个人，很酷
I'm going to see
我要去看看
code and now what I'm going to try and
代码，现在我要尝试的是
do is actually add a person method post
做的实际上是添加一个人方法
does not provide okay running into
不能正常运行
another error get oh I forgot to add
另一个错误得到哦，我忘了补充
something a transactional this has to be
事务性的东西
done in the context of a transaction
在交易中完成
because we're updating the database and
因为我们正在更新数据库，
I think that might be my problem there
我认为那可能是我的问题
we go
我们去
so you'll notice that there's actually
所以您会注意到实际上
an ID being created for me
正在为我创建一个ID
so panache actually provides automatic
所以panache实际上提供了自动
ID generation out-of-the-box if you want
开箱即用生成ID
to use your own strategy panache
使用自己的策略
supports that as well right
也支持这一点
okay so with all of this in mind what
好吧，请记住所有这些
we're gonna do is go back to our code
我们要做的是回到我们的代码
and we're gonna add one more method here
我们将在这里添加另一种方法
we're gonna say it gets this time we're
我们要说这一次我们得到了
gonna get a specific person so we're
要找到一个特定的人，所以我们
going to specify the ID and we are going
要指定ID，我们要
to seed public let's see we're going to
播种大众，让我们看看我们要
make it return a string get person at
使它返回一个字符串，使人在
path per am so we have two paths per am
每条路径，所以我们每条路径有两条
ID long ID here we go so what we're
ID long ID我们要走了，所以我们
gonna do is then find the person person
然后要做的就是找到那个人
person to do a lookup by ID it's
通过ID进行查询的人
actually really easy with panache we
实际上，使用Panache真的很容易
just say person dot find by ID and we're
只是说通过ID找到人点，我们
going to pass in the ID and we're gonna
要传递ID，我们将
return something here so what we're
在这里返回一些东西，所以我们
going to return is a string but we're
要返回的是一个字符串，但我们
going to kind of build this string from
打算从
scratch so we're gonna call the hello
从头开始，所以我们要打个招呼
method so I'm gonna greet this person
方法，所以我要和这个人打招呼
plus and it's person's name person name
加号和人名人名
plus remember it's a public property but
另外请记住，这是一个公共财产，但是
if they were a getter it would call the
如果他们是吸气剂，它将称为
getter so that's some really nice
吸气剂，这真的很不错
feature
特征
okay oops you are person dot age plus
好吧，您是人点年龄加上
years old okay so that works now what
岁，好，现在可以使用了
you're gonna find is if we actually try
你会发现如果我们真的尝试
to list all the people they're going to
列出所有他们要去的人
be gone that's because what panache is
之所以消失是因为
really doing under the scenes as its
真的在幕后做
dropping the class loader and basically
删除类加载器，基本上
reloading the entire application from
从重新加载整个应用程序
scratch so anything that's in memory is
从头开始，所以内存中的任何内容都是
lost unless you persist it somewhere
迷失，除非你坚持到某个地方
like a database right so what I'm going
像数据库一样，所以我要去
to do is I'm going to actually post
我要做的是实际发布
these people back create these people
这些人回来创造这些人
again now if I actually want to go and
现在，如果我真的想去
just list that one person what you'll
只是列出一个人你会做什么
see is it saying howdy Duke you are
看到这是说你好吗杜克
twenty five years old right so now if we
二十五岁，现在，如果我们
go back to our fallback logic right what
回到我们的后备逻辑吧
we want to do then is basically do a
我们要做的就是基本上要做一个
fallback if there was a problem with
如果出现问题，请回退
making this remote call to person so
拨打此人的电话
what's I'm looking for our here we go
我在找什么我们在这里走
for our hello call right so what happens
我们打个招呼吧，那会发生什么
if this fails well let's find out so I
如果失败了，让我们找出答案，我
am going to go back to open shift kill
我要回去倒班杀
all copies all instances of this
全部复制此项目的所有实例
application so now we have nothing and
应用程序，所以现在我们什么都没有了，
running
跑步
so hopefully this time it will actually
所以希望这次真的
call the fallback logic which it does so
调用它这样做的后备逻辑
that's pretty cool
太酷了
all right so what if we want to do some
好吧，如果我们想做些什么
additional logic around counting how
有关如何计算的其他逻辑
many times this method fails and then
很多时候此方法失败，然后
being able to view that and a graph on a
能够查看该图和一个图形
dashboard for instance right so if we go
例如正确的仪表板，所以如果我们去
back to our our presentation micro
回到我们的演示文稿微型
profile also has let's see where we had
个人资料也让我们看看我们在哪里
here micro profile metrics so with micro
在这里，微型配置文件指标与微
profile metrics I can actually create
我可以实际创建的个人资料指标
custom metrics in my application and
我的应用程序中的自定义指标
this gives you an idea of some of the
这使您对一些
metrics that are available
可用指标
what I'm going to use is that counter
我要用的是那个柜台
some of this is changed with micro
其中一些已通过微更改
profile metrics 2.0 but right now we're
个人资料指标2.0，但现在我们
using my profile metrics 1.1 right but
使用我的个人资料指标1.1对，但是
what you get out of the box with metrics
您可以从指标中获得什么
is an endpoint slash metrics that can be
是端点斜线指标，可以是
pulled by four exist for example
例如被四拉
Prometheus right and with with that you
普罗米修斯与您同在
get some base metrics that are required
获得一些必需的基本指标
by Mikah profile things like you know
由米卡（Mikah）进行个人资料，例如您知道
CPUs and memory available some vendor
一些供应商提供的CPU和内存
specific metrics if a vendor wants to
供应商想要的特定指标
provide that and then of course your
提供那个，然后当然是你的
application metrics right so let's
正确的应用程序指标，让我们
actually try and add a metric in here so
实际上尝试在此处添加指标
what I'm going to do is see here come
我要做的就是看到这里来
back back here we're going to track a
回到这里，我们将跟踪
metric I'm going to say at inject a
指标，我要在注入
metric and we're going to give this
指标，我们将给出这个
metric and name of hello fail the number
指标和名称您好号码失败
of times the hello method fails and
有时hello方法失败，
we're gonna make this a counter okay so
我们将使它成为反击，所以
let's do a little bit of Auto importing
让我们做一些自动导入
there we go now every time the method
每次方法我们都去那里
fails some of these if you can find the
如果您发现其中一些失败，
we're gonna increment the counter so I'm
我们要增加计数器，所以我
gonna say counter increment right
要说计数器增加对
okay so let's add a couple more people
好吧，让我们再增加几个人
because remember we reloaded so we're
因为记得我们重新加载了
gonna add our people again now what I'm
现在要再次添加我们的人
going to do is hit the metrics endpoint
要做的是击中指标端点
let's see metrics so this is in
让我们看看指标，这是
Prometheus format by default but you can
默认为Prometheus格式，但您可以
see there's some vendor specific metrics
看到有一些特定于供应商的指标
there's some base metrics that are
有一些基本指标是
required by micro profile and now what
微型配置文件需要什么，现在又需要什么
I'm going to do is see if I can do a
我要做的就是看我是否可以
grep I'm gonna look for our application
我要寻找我们的应用程序
metric and then you can see see so far
指标，然后您可以看到到目前为止
it says it's failed zero times so let's
它说它失败了零次，所以让我们
try this again
再试一次
it should fall
它应该下降
back whenever we get this person let's
回来，只要我们得到这个人，就让我们
see hello now let's go back and count it
大家好，现在回去数一下
again and you'll see that it's failed
再次，你会发现它失败了
three times right so now I can keep
三遍，现在我可以继续
track of application metrics and created
跟踪应用程序指标并创建
for fauna dashboard running inside of
用于在内部运行的动物仪表板
kubernetes and everything so I think
kubernetes和其他一切，我认为
maybe at this point we got a few minutes
也许在这一点上，我们有几分钟
left I don't know if I'm gonna have time
离开，我不知道我是否有时间
to compile this down to a native binary
将其编译为本地二进制文件
well maybe I'll try but I have to do one
好吧，也许我会尝试，但是我必须做一个
thing first
首先
I'm gonna change the endpoint here
我要在这里更改端点
because when we're running in I forgot
因为当我们跑步时我忘了
to make this as a part of the profiles
使其成为个人资料的一部分
so we are going to do colon 8080 slash
所以我们要做冒号8080斜线
hello when we're running in inside of
你好，当我们在里面跑
kubernetes the URL for the service is
kubernetes服务的URL是
going to be different because we're not
会有所不同，因为我们不是
going through an external gateway an
通过外部网关
external proxy so there we go so I'm
外部代理，所以我们去了，所以我
gonna try and compile this down to a
尝试将其编译为
binary and we should be utilizing these
二进制文件，我们应该利用这些
database properties when we do that so
这样做时的数据库属性
first I'm going to do maybe I'll do it
首先我要去做，也许我会去做
right now before I forget is I am going
在我忘记要走之前
to modify my docker file to make sure
修改我的docker文件以确保
that I'm specifying and the right
我指定的和正确的
profile equals prod there we go and
配置文件等于产品，我们去了，
we're gonna compile it down to a native
我们将其编译为本地
binary by by specifying native but we
通过指定本地二进制文件，但我们
want it to be in a Linux container so we
希望它在Linux容器中，所以我们
got to compile it into a Linux binary
必须将其编译为Linux二进制文件
right so that's what this line right
对，所以这条线对
here is it's basically says build it as
这基本上就是说将其构建为
a docker image which is gonna be a Linux
一个将成为Linux的docker镜像
binary alright this is going to take
二进制好吧，这将需要
maybe more time than we have left but
也许比我们剩下的时间更多，但是
we're going to give it a shot Tanya I'm
我们要给它一个镜头Tanya我是
not sure how we handle QA so far
不确定到目前为止我们如何处理质量检查
seems that you're doing just the perfect
看来你做的很完美
job search in silver anyone have
白银求职者
questions around micro profile or quark
有关微轮廓或夸克的问题
is please enter them into the chat and I
请输入他们的聊天内容，我
apologize for having some some technical
对某些技术表示歉意
difficulties along the way don't really
一路上的困难不是真的
my life coding was a little bit better
我的生活编码好一点了
than that
比起那个来说
because sound came across pretty well
因为声音传得很好
because I was having problems on my own
因为我自己有问题
but I think it's a problem okay I'm
但我认为这是一个问题
double checking my cable modem and it
仔细检查我的电缆调制解调器
looks to be okay okay while it builds
看起来还可以吧
let's see here
让我们看看这里
maybe what I'll do is show you a little
也许我会告诉你一点
bit about getting started with Korkis if
如果要开始使用Korkis，如果
you want to get started with Korkis go
您想开始使用Korkis go
to quark SiO there's literally a get
夸克SiO有字面上的意思
started page where it will take you
开始页面将带您
through some of the steps that I've
通过我已经完成的一些步骤
showed you here about creating your
向您展示了有关创建您的
first application that you know use the
您知道的第一个应用程序使用
maven plug-in to create a project kind
Maven插件创建项目种类
of like you saw and we do here how to
就像你看到的，我们在这里如何
build a native image how to use maven
建立本机映像如何使用Maven
and Gradle Gradle is also supported with
并且Gradle Gradle也受支持
Korkis there's actually I'll go to
Korkis实际上我会去
extensions first there are many many
扩展首先有很多很多
extensions like I mentioned that cover
像我提到的扩展
all sorts of functionality that you can
您可以使用的各种功能
use with Korkis if you're running in JVM
如果您在JVM中运行，请与Korkis一起使用
mode you could pretty much use any Java
模式，您几乎可以使用任何Java
library that you want the issue is when
您要发布的库是何时
if you want to compile down to a native
如果您想编译成本机
binary then you might run into some
二进制文件，那么您可能会遇到一些
issues right where you'll have to use
问题就在您必须使用的地方
Quercus extensions or do a little bit of
Quercus扩展或做一点
extra work or work with the framework
额外的工作或使用框架
provider to kind of support native
提供本地支持的提供商
native development
本土发展
there's guides for all of this
所有这些都有指南
functionality with Korkis there's a
Korkis的功能有一个
guide on that specific functionality if
有关该特定功能的指南，如果
you have code within your organization
您的组织内有代码
and your own custom frameworks we have a
和您自己的自定义框架，我们有一个
guy that kind of explains to you well if
如果你能很好地向你解释的家伙
it doesn't compile down to native binary
它不会编译为本地二进制文件
out of the box and you can create your
开箱即用，您可以创建自己的
own extension so that your framework
自己的扩展，以便您的框架
providers
提供者
in your organization can make them an
在您的组织中可以使他们成为
extension that other folks can use right
其他人可以使用的扩展名
so we've got guides on doing you know
所以我们有指导您了解
database manipulation there's a Mongo
数据库操作有一个Mongo
extension being worked on right now all
扩展目前正在全部进行中
sorts of web style extensions some of
各种网络样式扩展
them I showed you messaging with Kafka
他们我向您展示了与Kafka的消息传递
and reactive messaging with micro
和微动响应消息
profile reactive messaging hmm
个人资料反应式消息传递
some security extensions so there's
一些安全扩展，所以有
actually quite a bit there I think
我认为实际上有很多
there's something we had some camel
有些东西我们有骆驼
guides here too let's see how our
这里的指南也让我们看看我们的
compilation is doing oops wear it this
编译在做哎呀，穿这个
way and it's still building yeah I don't
方式，而且还在建设，是的，我没有
think it's gonna build in time so it
认为它会及时建立，所以它
takes about five minutes but one thing I
大约需要五分钟，但我要做一件事
did do and you might find this kind of
确实做到了，您可能会发现这种
interesting is I kind of pre ran this in
有趣的是我有点预先运行了
another
另一个
openshift project right so if we go to
openshift项目正确，所以如果我们去
kind of like my backup project you'll
有点像我的备份项目
see that I have this running I have the
看到我正在运行我有
person project running and what's really
人员项目正在运行，实际上是什么
cool is because Korkis is so efficient I
很酷是因为Korkis非常高效
can just run just a ton of copies of
只能运行大量的副本
this I'll just do you know 34 now here
我现在就知道34
for the database I'll go and I'll create
对于数据库，我将创建
maybe six copies what I've actually done
大概是我实际完成的六份拷贝
I did this yesterday kind of testing the
我昨天做了这种测试
limits of what I could do with this on
我对此的限制
my machine and I had 200 copies of hello
我的机器和我有200份问候
running as a native Java natively
作为本机Java本地运行
compiled Java application along with 25
编译的Java应用程序以及25
copies of the person project so you
人员项目的副本，以便您
could see it scaling up right so it's
可以看到它按比例放大，所以
actually starting these natively
实际上是从本地开始的
compiled Java applications like super
超级编译的Java应用程序
fast right and then I've got about half
快速正确，然后我大约有一半
the CPUs allocated to this virtual
分配给该虚拟机的CPU
machine so it's actually pretty cool and
机器，所以它实际上很酷，
I guess with that we're at the top of
我想我们处于最重要的位置
the hour
小时
I apologize for some of the technical
对于某些技术问题，我深表歉意。
difficulties I ran into I didn't get to
我遇到的困难我没有去
show you micro profile whole health
向您展示微观状况
checks
支票
and so with micro profile health checks
等等，通过微型个人资料健康检查
there's the ability to kind of expose
有能力暴露
the health the lightness and readiness
健康，轻松和准备
of your application to your to the
您的应用程序到您的
environment in this case kubernetes so
在这种情况下的环境kubernetes这样
that if it sees that it's it's it's not
如果它看到的是不是
life it'll kill the Potter you start it
生活会杀死你开始的波特
right or if the pot isn't ready it won't
对的，如果锅还没准备好，就不会
direct traffic to it so that's a quick
将流量引向该站点，因此很快
summary of micro profile health again
再次简要描述微状况健康
sorry for the technical difficulties no
对不起，技术上的困难
matter how many times you practice this
无论练习多少次
and trust me I did there always seems to
相信我，我一直在那里
be issues Tanya I don't know if there's
是问题Tanya，我不知道是否有
any close closing verbage that you
你的任何接近的结束语
wanted to add all right well I think we
我想补充一点好吧，我想我们
are actually done here I think we seem
我想我们似乎在这里完成了
to have lost Tanya and I think we're
失去了Tanya，我想我们
still recording all right Oh anyway
还是在录音吗
thanks everyone for joining I apologize
谢谢大家的加入，我深表歉意
you can find me on at edge a Klingon on
你可以在克林贡边缘找到我
Twitter and although I'm kind of
Twitter，尽管我有点
embarrassed with some of the problems I
为我遇到的一些问题感到尴尬
ran into so just be nice alright thanks
碰到了，所以很好，谢谢
bye
再见